# Luis Camacho III

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

**■** (612)-715-7023 · ★luiscamachoiii@gmail.com · ⊕Apple Valley, MN · <u>Ølinkedin</u> · <u>Øgithub</u> · <u>Øfacebook</u>

## **SUMMARY**

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer with 14+ years of experience designing and delivering awesome web and desktop applications. An effective leader, communicator, and collaborator and loves working with code and working with people and is currently looking to join a new team creating life-changing software applications!

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### RunSafe Security · Senior Software Engineer

- McLean, VA (Remote) · May 2024 Nov 2024
  - ★ Planned, implemented, and delivered a complete redesign of customer facing application
  - ★ Developed authentication and authorization with 100% code coverage using e2e and component Cypress tests
  - ★ Enhanced UX and branding by integrating multi-color themes using MUIv6
  - ★ Achieved 100% code coverage on Node.js backend with Vitest

#### Intertech · Full Stack Software Consultant

Deepcell · Apr 2022 - May 2024

- ★ Only candidate in company's history to score 100% on frontend technical assessment.
- ★ Wrote 99% of code for **Axon**: the cytotechnologist data suite: **\$\text{\text{YIDEO}}**
- ★ Created complex svg animation built on Electron to visualize cells moving through channels into wells: <a href="VIDEO">VIDEO</a>
- ★ Maintained and enhanced flask/python backend and prototyped new tools using Streamlit

Homepoint · Nov 2021 - Apr 2022

- ★ Enthusiastically mentored junior team members regarding React best practices surrounding reusability and unit testing with Jest/Enzyme.
- ★ Completely rebuilt broken authentication process using azure-msal and azure-react
- ★ Reduced state management redux code by 75%

RSM · Jul 2019 - Oct 2021

- $\bigstar$  Incorporated Azure services such as service bus, functions, and blog storage into tax service application
- ★ Future proofed C# code with TDD
- ★ Created customized npm <u>**Soidc-client</u>** package and documentation which was used internally with auth components across multiple teams</u>
- ★ Used EF-core code first approach and constructed database with generated scripts

#### **Emerson · Lead Senior Software Engineer**

- Shakopee, MN · Feb 2014 June 2019
  - ★ Lead developer for <u>\$\infty\$5408 Level</u> project, working closely with BU's
  - ★ Led all issue analysis meetings, listening to BU's pain points and requests
  - ★ Promoted and implemented WyBuild deployment, saving 100 dev hours/yr.

#### **Thomson Reuters · Software Engineer**

- **Eagan**, MN · May 2009 Feb 2014
  - ★ Implemented <u>**SAP MII**</u> through full project cycle
  - ★ Created dashboards using vanilla HTML/CSS/Javascript and some JQuery.
  - ★ Enhanced data driven reporting with complex SQL data procedures

#### **SKILLS**

# **■** Web Development

- → Typescript/Javascript, HTML/CSS, React, Angular, NextJs, Node.js, Express
- → Redux, RTK, easy-peasy
- → MUI, JSS, Chakra UI, Primefaces
- → plotly-js, nivo
- → axios, Bootstrap, Formik, react-query, react-table

#### Backend

- → C#, .NET, Python
- → WPF
- → Sequelize, EF Core

#### Cloud Platforms

→ Azure, Google Cloud, Firebase

## 📊 Data and Databases

→ SQL, SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL

# **X** Tools

→ Git, npm, Poetry, Pip, Docker, Tilt, Dozzle, RedGate, Figma, Streamlit, DataDog

#### Testing & QA

- → Cypress, Vitest, Jest, React Testing Library
- → Enzyme, XUnit, Moq, Autofixture

# **Devops & Project Management**

→ Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Jira

### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelors of Science, Computer Science

<u>University of Minnesota, Twin Cities · 2008 - 2010</u>

#### **PERSONAL**

- Teaching, public speaking
- Playing guitar, singing, organizing concerts
- Sports, lifting weights

# luiscamachoiii.com

~Comprehensive 10-page resume available upon request~